A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic works great on hearts tired by modern society!
تُعالج استنتاجات كونان القلوب المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
Today's case is Shinigami Jinnai and his devious crime!
!قضيّة اليوم عن ملك الموت جينّاي وجريمته الشبحية
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Shinigami Jinnai Murder Case
جريمة قتل ملك الموت جينّاي
Really? I liked it...
تظنّ ذلك؟ نال إعجابي
Nanjo Hayato (42)- Movie Actor
(42) نانجو هاياتو ممثل أفلام
Nanjo Miyuki (37)- Nanjo's Wife
(37) نانجو ميوكي زوجة نانجو
Gimme a break...
حقّاً؟
Right in here, Detective Mori.
تفضّل، هنا يا متحرّي موري
This is quite a nice office!
يا له من مكتبٍ جميل
Here you are.
تفضّلوا
This is Mori Kogoro-san, the famous detective.
ساتومي-سان
Yoshino Satomi (28)- Nanjo's Manager
(يوشينو ساتومي (28 مديرة أعمال نانجو
I'm Nanjo Hayato's manager,
أنا مديرة أعمال نانجو هاياتو
Yoshino Satomi.
أُدعى يوشينو ساتومي
Satomi-san. Show it to him...
ساتومي-سان، هلّا أريتِ موري-سان تلك؟
But, ma'am!
...لكن سيّدتي
Just show it to him.
لا يهمّ، أعطه إيّاها
Alright...
حسناً
What the...
...هـ-هذه
- "I am coming for Nanjo Hayato tonight. - Shinigami Jinnai"
.سآتي لأخذ حياة نانجو هاياتو الليلة" "ملك الموت جينّاي-
A warning from Shinigami Jinnai?!
تحذير من ملك الموت جينّاي؟
It was in the office mailbox this morning.
كان في صندوق بريد المكتب هذا الصباح
Did you take it to the police?
هل أريتموها للشرطة؟
No...
...كلا
There's no need.
لا حاجة لذلك
It's obviously a prank!
إنّه مقلب بكلّ وضوح
But, Honey!
...لكن يا عزيزي
I told you not to do anything!
!أخبرتك ألّا تتصرّفي من تلقاء نفسك
Sorry, but I must ask you to leave.
المعذرة، لكن سأطلب منك المغادرة
But, Nanjo-san! Your wife is this worried about you...
لكن يا نانجو-سان، زوجتك قلقةٌ عليك
But, still!
...لكن
Anyway, I'm busy! Get out!
!بأيّ حال، أنا مشغول لذا غادروا
Yoshino-kun. You can leave for today, too.
يوشينو-كن، يمكنك الانصراف أيضاً
Behind me is the office of Nanjo Hayato,
ورائي مكتب المُمثل نانجو هاياتو-سان
who has received a death threat from Shinigami Jinnai.
الذي تلقّى رسالة تهديد بالقتل من ملك الموت جينّاي
It's just past 9:00.
تجاوزت الساعة التاسعة للتوّ
Will Shinigami Jinnai appear as warned?
هل سيظهر ملك الموت جينّاي كما قال في تحذيره؟
The famous Mori Kogoro-san is also present,
يوجد في المسرح المتحرّي الشهير موري كوغورو-سان أيضاً
so the tension is high!
!فالتوتّر مرتفع
Hello. I'm the great Mori Kogoro.
مرحباً، أنا المتحرّي الشهير موري كوغورو
OK, we're done! Take a short break!
انتهينا! لنأخذ استراحةً قصيرة
Everything will be all right.
ستكون الأمور بخيرٍ سيّدتي
The culprit can't make a move as long as we're here!
لن يستطيع المُجرم الإقدام على شيء بوجودنا هنا وتأهّبنا
Now, now, Mori-san.
على رويدك يا موري-سان
There's no need to get excited;
لا حاجة للتحمّس
Ohno Tadao (45)- TV Director
(أونو تاداو (45 مخرج تلفازيّ
he's not gonna show.
فلن يظهر ملك الموت جينّاي
What do you mean?
ما قصدك؟
It's obvious that Nanjo did this just to promote the movie!
هذه مجرد مسرحية من تدبير نانجو للترويج لفيلمه بكلّ وضوح
How dare you say that?!
!كيف تجرؤ على قول هذا؟
Please, calm down, ma'am!
!على رسلك سيّدتي، اهدئي
Let's go, Conan-kun!
لنذهب يا كونان-كن
Huh? Isn't that Satomi-san, his manager?
ماذا؟ أليست تلك مديرته ساتومي-سان؟
You're right! I guess she didn't go home yet...
معك حق، لم ترجع لمنزلها بعد إذاً
She could watch the office from there!
يمكنها مشاهدة المكتب من هناك
She's probably worried too!
لعلّها تشعر بالقلق
Let's go, Conan-kun!
هيّا بنا يا كونان-كن
So Nanjo-san's the only one here this late...
نانجو-سان وحده هو المتبقّي في هذا الوقت إذاً
Hey, where's Ohno-san?
أين أونو-سان؟
He went to the bathroom...
قال أنّه ذاهبٌ للحمّام
What do we do next?
ماذا نفعل تالياً؟
I'll go look for him...
سأذهب للبحث عنه
What is it?
ما الخطب؟
Over there!
!ذ-ذاك
Shinigami Jinnai!
!ملك الموت جينّاي
Hey! Get the camera!
!الكاميرا! هاتوا الكاميرا
Give yourself up!
!سلّم نفسك
Damn! I lost him!
!سحقاً! فقدت أثره
Nanjo-san's in danger!
!يا عمّ! نانجو-سان في خطر
Crap!
!تـ-تبّاً
Satomi-san! Why are you here?!
ساتومي-سان! لمَ أنت هنا؟
I was in that burger shop when I saw Shinigami Jinnai
كنتُ في مطعم الهامبرغر ورأيتُ ملك الموت جينّاي
run inside the building!
!يدخل المبنى
What?!
!ماذا؟
Dammit!
!تبّاً
No you don't, Conan-kun!
!لا يمكنك يا كونان-كن
But...
...لكن
Conan-kun! Was that--
...كونان-كن، أكان ذلك
The culprit's still on the 7th floor! I just saw his shadow!
!لا يزال المجرم في الطابق السابع يا عمّ !رأيتُ ظلّه للتو
Alright!
!حسنٌ
Damn, what's this tape for?!
!تبّاً! لمَ هذا الشريط هنا؟
Vinyl tape?
شريط لاصق؟
So the killer disappeared from the scene, Mori-kun?
اختفى القاتل من المسرح إذاً يا موري-كن؟
Yeah, Inspector.
أجل حضرة المفتّش
The windows are all locked from the inside,
كلّ النوافذ هنا مُقفلة من الداخل، فلم يفتحها
and the elevator and the stairs are the only way off the 7th floor.
والمصعد والأدراج هما السبيلان الوحيدان للخروج من الطابق السابع
But he was gone when we rushed in.
لكننا لم نجد له أثراً بعدما أسرعنا إلى هنا
And you're certain that nobody left the building?
وأنت متأكد أنّ لا أحد غادر المبنى؟
Yes, we and the reporters were out front the whole time...
نعم، كنتُ مع المراسلين أمام المبنى طوال الوقت
But what about the emergency stairs?
لكن ماذا عن أدراج الطوارئ؟
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
The emergency stairs here meet up with the 1st-floor elevator
أدراج طوارئ هذا المبنى تتّصل بالطريق المؤدي للمصعد في الطابق الأوّل
and lead to the same exit.
وتنتهي لنفس المخرج
I watched the emergency stairs, but nobody used them.
كنتُ أراقب أدراج الطوارئ ولم يستعملها أحد
So the killer just disappeared like smoke...
أي أنّ القاتل اختفى كالدخان؟
What's wrong, Conan-kun?
ما الخطب يا كونان-كن؟
Doesn't it seem strange?
ألا تظنّين الأمر غريباً؟
We saw the killer standing at the window when the lights came on.
رأينا القاتل يقف عند النافذة عندما أُضيئت المصابيح
But the light switch is by the door.
لكنّ مفتاحها بجوار الباب
How exactly did he turn the lights on?
كيف أضاء القاتل مصابيح الغرفة؟
That is strange...
ذلك غريبٌ بالفعل
Why did the killer turn the lights on after murdering Nanjo-san?
لمَ أضاء القاتل المصابيح بعد قتله نانجو-سان؟
And--
...كما
Why on earth did the killer leave this vinyl tape behind?
لمَ ترك القاتل الشريط اللاصق بهذا الشكل؟
Most likely so we would trip and get tangled up in it,
لعلّه فعل ذلك كي يعرقلنا بعدما لاحقناه
allowing him to make his getaway.
فيستطيع استغلاله للهرب
But you're the only one who tripped on it!
!لكنّك كنت الوحيد الذي تعرقل
An article check request...
...طلب مراجعة نصّ
Nanjo-sama, please look over the article.
:إلى نانجو-ساما راجع النصّ من فضلك
10:03 pm. Just before he was murdered...
العاشرة وثلاث دقائق مساءً، أي قُبيل قتل نانجو-سان
Just about the time Shinigami Jinnai appeared in the park...
ظهر ملك الموت جينّاي في الحديقة قرابة ذاك الوقت
But isn't this--
...لكن أليس
Alright, you!
!يا شقيّ
Don't touch that!
!لا تلمس هذا
That's an interview that's being published in a magazine next week.
هذا طلب مراجعة نصّ مقالة ستُنشر في مجلّة الأسبوع القادم
Nanjo-san was waiting for it to arrive tonight.
كان نانجو-سان ينتظر وصولها الليلة
Let go of me!
!دعوني
Inspector! This shady character was lurking about!
حضرة المفتّش، كان هذا الرجل المُريب يتسكّع في الجوار
How rude! I'm no shady character!
!يا للفظاظة! لستُ شخصاً مريباً
Ohno-san! Where have you been?!
أونو-سان! أين كنت؟
I returned from the bathroom to find everyone gone,
لم أجد أحداً بعدما رجعت من الحمّام
so I was looking around the park!
فبحثتُ في أرجاء الحديقة
So it was you who killed my husband!
!كان أنت! أنت من قتل زوجي
What are you talking about?!
لحظة! ما الذي تقولينه؟
Come to think of it, you're the only one without an alibi!
صحيح... أنت الوحيد بلا حجّة غياب بين المتواجدين في مسرح الجريمة
You were still bitter about the accident three years ago...
كنت لا تزال حاقداً عليه ...بعد الحادثة قبل ثلاثة أعوام
...so you killed him!
!لذا قتلته
That's insane!
!سـ-سخافة
What is she referring to?
ما هذه الحادثة التي وقعت قبل ثلاثة أعوام؟
I work on an entertainment show now,
أعمل في برنامج ترفيهيّ الآن
but I was once a movie director.
لكنّي كنت مخرج أفلام
Until the accident three years ago during the filming of Shinigami Jinnai...
حتّى حادثة وقعت أثناء تصوير فيلم لملك الموت جينّاي قبل ثلاثة أعوام
The designated stuntman never showed up that day...
لم يظهر بديل أدوار المجازفة ذاك اليوم مهما انتظرنا
We have no choice. We'll do it without him.
ليس باليد حيلة، سنمثّل المشهد دونه
I dunno, Nanjo. It's too dangerous!
!لا يصحّ ذلك يا نانجو! المشهد خطر جداً
You can handle it, right, Kitano?
يمكنك تنفيذه، صحيح يا كيتانو؟
Kitano Hiroyuki (28)- Movie Actor
(28) كيتانو هيرويوكي ممثل أفلام
Up-and-coming actors need
على الممثلين الصاعدين التمكّن
to be able to do this much.
من تنفيذ هذا القدر على الأقل
Yeah...
...أ-أجل
Director! I'll do it!
سأفعلها حضرة المخرج
But...
...لكن
Kitano-kun had agreed, so filming began upon Nanjo's insistence.
وافق الممثل المعنيّ كيتانو-كن، فبدأ التصوير بعد إلحاح نانجو
The car flipped over and exploded.
لكنّ السيّارة انقلبت وانفجرت
Kitano-kun was killed.
ومات كيتانو-كن
I took full responsibility and gave up the director's chair.
تحمّلتُ المسؤولية كاملةً وتركتُ منصب المُخرج
I did resent Nanjo.
أبغضت نانجو حقّاً
But there's someone who resented him much more right there!
لكن يوجد هنا من يبغض نانجو أكثر منّي بكثير
After all, she was Kitano-kun's lover!
فقد كانت هي حبيبة كيتانو-كن
Is this true?!
أهذا صحيح؟
Yes. Kitano Hiroyuki was my lover.
نعم، كان كيتانو هيرويوكي حبيبي بالفعل
I worked for the same agency as a 2nd-rate action movie actress.
كنتُ أعمل لنفس الوكالة كممثلة أفلام إثارة وتشويق من الدرجة الثانية
Yes, it was a terrible accident! But I don't blame Nanjo-san for it!
!كانت حادثة مؤسفة بالفعل، لكنّي لا ألوم نانجو-سان عليها
Satomi-san was out front with us when Nanjo-san was killed!
كانت ساتومي-سان معنا أمام المبنى وقت مقتل نانجو-سان
Oh yeah! I caught Shinigami Jinnai on tape in the park!
!صحيح! صوّرتُ ملك الموت جينّاي في الحديقة
What?! So that should show--
...ماذا؟! إن شاهدناه إذاً
There's a VCR on the 6th floor!
!يوجد مشغّل فيديو في الطابق السادس
I'll go set it up!
سأذهب لتجهيزه
Come to think of it, why did the killer show himself in the park?
بالمناسبة، لمَ أظهر القاتل نفسه في الحديقة؟
The same with the window locks-- there must be some reason!
الأمر ينطبق على ظلّ النافذة، لا بدّ من وجود سبب
It came from downstairs!
!أتى من الطابق السفليّ
Come on!
!تعال بسرعة
The stairs are faster!
!الأدراج أسرع
Shinigami Jinnai just--
...ملك الموت جينّاي قد
What?!
!ماذا؟
Then Shinigami Jinnai came out of the office, fired, and ran off?
وأطلق ملك الموت جينّاي عليكِ النار فجأةً بعدما خرج من المكتب
Yes...
نـ-نعم
That's odd. It's exactly one hour since Nanjo-san was killed.
هذا غريب، مضت ساعة تماماً مُذ قُتل نانجو-سان
Did he hide in the building and avoid police detection the whole time?
هل اختبأ المجرم طوال ذاك الوقت في المبنى متوارياً عن أنظار الشرطة؟
And why did he shoot, anyway?
ولمَ أطلق عليها النار؟
Satomi-san was alone. Running off would've been far safer
...فقد كانت ساتومي-سان بمفردها، الهرب دون الإطلاق
than firing and attracting attention!
وتجنّب لفت الانتباه كان ليفيده أكثر
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
We finished examining the murder scene.
أنهينا تحليل ساحة الجريمة
Good work. Did you find the bullet?
شكراً، هل وجدتم الرصاصة؟
No. It probably flew outside through the emergency exit.
كلا، خرجت عبر مخرج الطوارئ غالباً
In which case, finding it will be difficult.
سيكون العثور عليها صعباً في تلك الحالة
Inspector. The video's all set.
حضرة المفتش، أنهينا تجهيز التصوير
Let's have a look.
فلنشاهد إذاً
Why's this one by itself?
لمَ هذا بمفرده؟
It's still warm.
لا يزال دافئاً
And it's not rewound!
!كما لم يُرجع شريطه
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
You shouldn't touch other people's things.
لا يصحّ بك لمس أغراض الآخرين
I'm sorry!
!آسف
Aha! I've figured out the killer's trick!
!هكذا إذاً! فهمت حيلة القاتل
But I need more proof!
لكن لا زلتُ بحاجة لدليل
That's it! That fax!
!صحيح! رسالة الفاكس تلك
Hey, Conan! Where're you going?
كونان! أين تذهب؟
Just as I thought!
!كما ظننت
No question about it! That person is the killer!
!لا شكّ في الأمر! القاتل هو ذاك الشخص
Hey! Conan! Quit running around!
!كونان! كفّ عن التجوّل
Huh? This is just that fax...
...ماذا؟ إنّها رسالة الفاكس تلك
What's so big about it?
ما المهمّ فيها؟
Hello?
مرحباً
Right.
نعم
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
It's Mori-san.
إنّه موري-سان
Thanks...
شكراً
Hello? Mori-kun?
مرحباً؟ موري-كن؟
What?! You solved the mystery?!
!ماذا؟ حللت اللغز؟
Yes. The killer didn't disappear.
نعم، لم يختف القاتل من مسرح الجريمة
He was never there in the first place!
بل لم يكن موجوداً من البداية
What?! What does that mean?
ماذا؟! ما قصدك؟
It means Nanjo-san was already dead when we got to the building.
أي أنّ نانجو-سان كان مقتولاً سلفاً عندما وصلنا أمام المبنى
But Conan-kun and the others saw the killer in the window!
لكنّ كونان-كن والبقيّة رأوا القاتل عبر النافذة
That was a trick the killer set up.
تلك كانت حيلة من إعداد القاتل
Trick?!
!حيلة؟
I'll demonstrate it for you. Have everyone come back upstairs.
سأوضّح الأمر لكم، لذا فليصعد الجميع للطابق السابع من فضلكم
Please bring some vinyl tape and fishing line as well.
أحضروا معكم شريطاً لاصقاً وخيط صيد سمك أيضاً
Vinyl tape and fishing line?
شريط لاصق وخيط صيد؟
It seems everyone's here, so I'll begin.
أتى الجميع، لذا سأبدأ
First, after murdering Nanjo-san,
،أوّلاً، بعدما قتل المجرمُ نانجو-سان
the killer cut the lights and placed the vinyl tape
أطفأ مصابيح الغرفة وألصق الشريط بالنافذة
on the window in a zigzag manner to create the shape of a person.
بخطوط متعرّجة لرسم شكل إنسان
Next, he affixed the fishing line to the area
...تالياً، ربط طرف خيط الصيد بالفجوة
between the elevator and the outer door.
بين المصعد والباب الخارجيّ
He then wrapped the line around the light switch in the office,
ثمّ لفّ الخيط ووضعه حول مفتاح المصابيح في المكتب وسحبه
and tied the end to the tape roll on the window.
وربط الطرف الآخر بالشريط اللاصق على النافذة
All that remained was for someone to call the elevator down...
ما تبقّى هو انتظار أن يضغط أحد ممن هلعوا للمبنى زرّ استدعاء المصعد للأسفل
The light made it look like someone was in the room.
هكذا إذا نظرت من الخارج، سيبدو لك أنّ الهيئة بالشريط اللاصق إنسان بتأثير الأنوار
The tape came undone when the line was pulled,
سيُنزع الشريط مع سحب الخيط
making it look like the person was crouching.
فيبدو كما لو أنّ الشخص قد سقط
When pulled far enough, the tape roll caught on the elevator,
مع سحب الشريط المستمر، وصلت لفافته باب المصعد
and then the line snapped, leaving the roll behind.
ثمّ انقطع خيط الصيد، فتبقّى الشريط اللاصق
But what about the gunshot?
لكن ماذا عن تلك الطلقة النارية؟
That was a cassette tape recording.
كانت صوتاً على شريط كاسيت
A cassette tape?
شريط كاسيت؟
Yes. The killer shot Nanjo-san with a silencer-equipped gun,
أجل، أردى الفاعلُ نانجو-سان قتيلاً بمسدّس مزوّد بكاتم للصوت
set up the elevator trick, took the stairs to the 6th floor,
نصب حيلة المصعد، ثمّ نزل للطابق السادس من أدراج الطوارئ
and put a tape with a gunshot on it in the stereo.
وأدخل شريط صوت عيار ناريّ مسجل في آلة التشغيل
There'd be no way to make certain the gunshot was heard below...
لا يمكنك معرفة الطابق الذي أُطلق فيه العيار الناريّ من أسفل المبنى بالفعل
The killer added fifteen minutes of silence to the start of the tape
أضاف القاتل 15 دقيقة فارغة لبداية الشريط
and used that time to appear in the park as Shinigami Jinnai
واستغلّ ذاك الوقت للظهور بهيئة ملك الموت جينّاي في الحديقة
and lure us to the building.
واستدراجنا للمبنى
The killer then met up and heard the gunshot with us to create an alibi.
التقى القاتل بنا بعدها واستمع للعيار الناريّ كي يخلق حجّة غياب لنفسه
Hold on a second! Does that mean the killer is--
...ا-انتظر! أتقصد أنّ القاتل
Yes! The only one capable of pulling off this trick...
...نعم، الوحيد القادر على تنفيذ هذه الحيلة
...was you, Yoshino Satomi-san!
!هي أنت يا يوشينو ساتومي-سان
But what was the second gunshot for?
لكن ما سبب الطلقة الثانية إذاً؟
The second gunshot wasn't meant to happen.
لم يكن يُفترض أن تحصل
Yoshino-san didn't realize the stereo was set on auto-rewind.
لم تدرك يوشينو-سان أنّ خيار إعادة إعادة التشغيل تلقائياً في جهاز التسجيل كان مُداراً
As it was a 60-minute tape, the same gunshot rang out one hour later!
،بما أنّ الشريط الذي استعملته كان من 60 دقيقة سمعنا الطلقة نفسها بعد مرور ساعة
When you went downstairs to set up the VCR,
عندما نزلتِ للطابق السفليّ ...لتجهيز جهاز التسجيل
you probably recovered the fishing line!
استرجعتِ خيط الصيد غالباً
Then the gunshot suddenly played!
وعندها سمعتِ صوت الطلقة فجأةً
Surprised, you quickly hid the tape and came up with a lie.
في دهشتك، أخفيتِ الشريط سريعاً واختلقتِ كذبة تخبريننا بها
There's no proof!
!لا يوجد لديك دليل
But there is.
الدليل موجود
Inspector. Have a look at the faxes.
حضرة المفتّش، انظر لرسائل الفاكس من فضلك
Alright...
حسناً
One of the pages should have bloodstains on it.
ستجد بقع دماء على إحدى الأوراق
That fax came in just as the murder was taking place.
فقد وصل فاكس لحظة وقوع الجريمة
Here it is!
!ها هو
In other words, the time on the page with bloodstains
أي أنّ الوقت المذكور على الورقة ببقع الدماء
is the real time Nanjo-san was murdered.
هو زمن قتل نانجو-سان الحقيقيّ
9:59 pm.
التاسعة وتسع وخمسون مساءً
We heard the gunshot at around 10:15.
سمعنا الطلقة أمام المبنى عند قرابة العاشرة والربع
That makes it fifteen minutes before then.
أي بعد 15 دقيقة
There should be a gunshot on that tape you took from Conan.
يُفترض أن يكون صوت الطلقة موجوداً على الشريط الذي أخذتِه من كونان قبل قليل
Plus, Shinigami Jinnai could move so nimbly in the park
كما أنّ حركة ملك الموت جينّاي المرنة في الحديقة
because you used to be an action movie actress.
كانت لأنّك ممثلة أفلام إثارة سابقة
You're right. I killed Nanjo-san.
معك حقّ، قتلتُ نانجو
To get revenge on him for killing Hiroyuki three years ago!
!للانتقام من قتله هيرويوكي قبل 3 أعوام
But that was an accident...
...لكن كان ذلك حادثاً
I thought so too at first!
ذلك ما ظننتُه بدايةً
But then I found Hiroyuki's diary.
لكنّي وجدتُ مذكّرة هيريوكي
The week before the accident,
،قبل الحادث بأسبوع
there was talk of him replacing Nanjo as Shinigami Jinnai!
ذُكر فيها أخذه لمكان نانجو في دور ملك الموت جينّاي
I joined Nanjo's agency as a manager to learn the truth about his death!
التحقتُ بوكالة نانجو وأصبحت مديرة أعماله لأكتشف حقيقة موته
And then a month ago, Nanjo got drunk and divulged everything!
!ثمّ قبل شهر، باح نانجو الثمل بكلّ شيء
Hey, Yoshino. Remember that kid who died three years ago
يوشينو، أتذكرين الشاب الذي مات قبل ثلاثة أعوام
during the filming of Shinigami Jinnai?
أثناء تصوير ملك الموت جينّاي؟
Yes. Didn't he get in an accident while doing his own stunt?
نـ-نعم، ألم يكن حادثاً أثناء تمثيله لمشهد خطر دون بديل؟
Accident, huh...
حادث؟
Accident, indeed...
...حادث إذاً
Here's something interesting.
سأخبركِ بأمر مثير
I lied to the stuntman so he wouldn't come that day.
كذبتُ على بديل الأدوار الخطرة كيلا يأتي ذاك اليوم
The kid was a beginner but thought he could steal my role!
،كان ذاك الفتى مجرّد مبتدئ !لكنّه ظنّ بإمكانه سرقة دوري
You know what this is?
أتعرفين ما هذا؟
No. What is it?
لا، ما هو؟
My good luck charm.
تميمة حظّي الحسن
A bolt that keeps a car's front wheels in place.
مسمار ملولب يثبّت إطارات السيّارة الأمامية
What?! That means--
...مـ-ماذا؟! إذاً
That's right! He didn't wait for an accident to happen!
!صحيح! لم ينتظر وقوع الحادثة
He killed Hiroyuki himself!
!بل قتل هيرويوكي بيديه
I wrote the letter to use the media as an alibi.
أرسلتُ التهديد لأستغلّ مراسلي الإعلام لصنع حجّة غياب
When I advised using it to promote the movie, Nanjo readily agreed.
عندما اقترحتُ الأمر على نانجو للترويج للفيلم، وافق من فوره
The rest was as you said.
الباقي كما قلت
Shinigami Jinnai versus Detective Mori Kogoro.
ملك الموت جينّاي ضدّ المتحرّي موري كوغورو
Looks like Shinigami Jinnai lost completely.
يبدو أنّ ملك الموت جينّاي غُلب تماماً
Of course he did!
!بالطبع
The word "unsolvable" isn't in Mori Kogoro's dictionary!
فكلمة "مستعصٍ" لا تتواجد !في قاموس موري كوغورو
And who do you have to thank for that?
وذلك بفضل من؟
Darn it! We'll just have to bust it down!
تبّاً! لا أمامنا سوى فتحه بالقوّة
None of their things came out positive?!
!لم تظهر آثار على أيّ من أغراضهم؟
The one behind this manipulated the victim in this empty office
تلاعب المجرم بالضحيّة في المكتب الذي لم يكن فيه أحد سواه
and poisoned him!
!وسمّمه
As if by magic!
كما لو كان سحراً
The Finance Company President Murder Case
جريمة قتل رئيس الشركة المالية
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Toilet.
مرحاض
Next episode's case is really tough.
!الحلقة القادمة معقّدة حقّاً
He smells fishy.
!(إنّه مشبوه (نتن
Oh, sorry.
آسف